Anneta Wamono

Kitchener, Ontario P: https://annetawamono.github.io/portfolio/ E: annetawamono@yahoo.com.au

Frontend Developer

An enthusiastic and dedicated freelance Web Developer and Designer with 3 years of experience developing websites for small businesses. Extremely organized with the ability to work independently of own initiative and wanting to gain more experience working as part of a successful team, demonstrating the motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining the highest of standards. Currently looking for a new and challenging position as a Frontend Developer where I can develop product building experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Studio Locale, Kitchener, ON

May 2022

Studio Locale is a marketing, design and development studio working with companies of all scales.

Web Developer Volunteer

Link Up Festival, Waterloo, ON

Jun 2020 - Jul 2021

Link Up is a yearly festival to celebrate the African Caribbean cultural diaspora in Waterloo.

- I brought my WordPress experience to a team of new web developer volunteers. I helped them upskill their website design, UX and development skills.
- I developed a plugin for their marketplace that allows festival vendors' information to be managed and displayed.

Freelancer

Cape Town, South Africa

Aug 2019 - Current

As a freelance web developer and designer, I often take my clients from design to production on their websites. My client's businesses cater to niche markets.

- I designed and developed an e-commerce store for a client that allows them to sell physical goods, digital goods and tickets.
- I improved the page performance of an inherited site by 50% to help improve my client's SEO ranking.
- I wrote articles and used targeted keywords to help improve the SEO ranking for my clients.

Design/Developer Intern

Karbon Black, Pretoria

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

Karbon Black is a digital design studio that provides branding, UI/UX and development services.

- I worked closely with a client to develop an MVP for his product which was used to secure investments.
- I trained with the Lead Designer and took on UX work in the company along with my development work.

University Tutor

University of Pretoria

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

The University of Pretoria is a tertiary education institution.

I was a tutor for modules Intro to Computer Science and Operating Systems.

Anneta Wamono Page 2

• I assisted lecturers with grading homework, organizing schedules and designing tasks, and assisting students taking a degree course in Computer Science.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Design and Development, Conestoga College.

May 2020 - Aug 2022

<u>Modules included:</u> Responsive site design, Javascript programming, Web security, Database design, MEAN development, Data visualisation

• This program is taught by instructors with many years of industry experience and it gave me insight into best practices and leading technology.

Classical Animation, Vancouver Film School.

Aug 2018 – Aug 2019

Main project: One traditionally animated short film and one digital short film.

• This program focuses on the 12 principles of animation, animated film production and visual arts.

BIS in Multimedia, University of Pretoria.

Jan 2015 - Dec 2017

<u>Modules included:</u> Data structures and algorithms, Software modelling, Concurrent systems <u>Main project:</u> A functional game MVP designed and developed by a group.

 This degree is a combination of computer science modules, visual design and human-computer interaction. It equipped me with the fundamentals of software development, as well as an overview of UX/UI design.

Courses:

- Member of frontendmentors.io
- Participant of hacktoberfest 2021
- Completed Vue.js 2 Academy by Chris Dixon

Software skills:

- Git/Github
- VSCode
- Google Workplace

- Figma
- Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch
- Adobe After Effects, Premiere, Animate